Charles M. Kurtz
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Correspondence, 1843-1940, undated, Series 2:
  - Letters, 1904, undated (Reel 4817, Frame 1319-1337)
    (May C. Bristol, Edmund Hayes, E.H. Wuerpel, Alfred Ruckstuhl, Statement re: New York Advisory Commission of Louisiana Purchase Exposition)
  - Correspondence, January-March, 1904 (Reel 4817, Frame 1338-1358)
    (Executive Commissioner for Russia at St. Louis Exposition, Kentucky Commission, Louisiana Purchase Exposition, Julia S. Kurtz, Stephenson family, Charles M. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, April - May, 1904 (Reel 4817, Frame 1359-1380)
    (Joseph C. Spriggs, Leonard Alimon?, Jeanne C.Martin, Curtis Bell for Metropolitan Camera Club, Holmes Smith, Stephenson family, Charles M. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, June 1-30, 1904 (Reel 4817, Frame 1381-1394)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Ralph H. Plumb)
  - Correspondence, July 1-30, 1904 (Reel 4817, Frame 1395-1411)
    (Ralph H. Plumb, Charles Ward Rhodes, Robert C. Ogden, Charles M. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, August-September, 1904 (Reel 4817, Frame 1412-1437)
    (James D. Spriggs, Henry Wolf, Louisiana Purchase Exposition Commission, A. Barthélemy, J.B. Botto, Robert Vonnoh, Marion Eddy, Stephenson family, Charles M. Kurtz, and Charles Ward Rhodes dated August 23, 1900)
  - Correspondence, October 1-15, 1904 (Reel 4817, Frame 1438-1451)
    (Edward R. Rice, John Getz, James D. Spriggs, J.C. Strauss, United States Government Board-Louisiana Purchase Exposition, Carl Hirschberg)
  - Correspondence, October 16-25, 1904 (Reel 4817, Frame 1452-1479)
    (Ralph H. Plumb, Cornelia Beantley Sage, Joseph Beres-German Society of Buffalo, M.M. Blanc, Geo. F. Brownell, E. Brige Harrison, Frank V. Dudley, L.A.C.W.-Mrs. Ward, Charles M. Kurtz, Willis O. Chapin, Edward R. Rice, W.M.R. French, Halsey C. Ives?)
  - Correspondence, October 26-31, 1904 (Reel 4817, Frame 1480-1493)
    (Imperial Japanese Commission, Mary May Blanc, Charles Ward Rhodes, Kurtz family, William L. Marcy, Cornelia Bentley Sage, Mary Henry Mosler)
  - Correspondence, November 1-10, 1904 (Reel 4818, Frame 1-17)
    (E. Burgess Warren, W. L. Lathrop, Charles Ward Rhodes, Robert W. Vonnoh, Charles M. Kurtz?, Charles Ward Rhodes, W.W. Thum)
  - Correspondence, November 11-15, 1904 (Reel 4818, Frame 18-34)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Maria Brooks, J. Craig Annan, Edmund Hayes, Arthur Hoeber, C. F. von Saltza, Emery H. Barton, Ralph H. Plumb)
  - Correspondence, November 16-20, 1904 (Reel 4818, Frame 35-57)
    (Edmund Hayes, Charles M. Kurtz, Fred F. Gottschalk, Edward B. Green, Wm. H. Coffin, J. A. Holmes-Universal Exposition Chair, Patty Thum)
  - Correspondence, November 21-2 (Reel 4818, Frame 58-112)
    (Florence N. Levy, Geo. F. Brownell, Julia S. Kurtz, Metropolitan Museum of Art, R. H. Plumb, Geo. P. Sawyer, C.F. von Saltza, Charles M. Kurtz, Josephine Redding-The Art Interchange, William Macbeth, Cornelia Bentley Sage-Buffalo Fine Arts Academy, Wm. A. Coffin, Edward Dufner, Augustus Lukeman, J.B. Botto, Henry Wolf)
  - Correspondence, December 1-5, 1904 (Reel 4818, Frame 113-128)
    (Edmund Hayes-Buffalo Fine Arts Academy, William H. Goodyear-Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences, Henry Wolf, Mark Bennitt for Louisiana Purchase Exposition, Carl Hirschberg, A.H. Griffith-Detroit Museum of Art, Charles M. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, December 6-10, 1904 (Reel 4818, Frame 129-152)
    (J.N. Adam, S. Seymour Thomas, Ruth Martin, Edward B. Green, Edward Robinson-Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, Edward Dufner, Edward Hayes, Commissioner General for Bulgaria, Harrison S. Morris, Ralph H. Plumb, R.W. Vonnoh, F. Morton-Brush & Pencil, Lydia Avery Coonley Ward)
  - Correspondence, December 11-15, 1904 (Reel 4818, Frame 153-173)
    (Carleton Wiggins, Emil Carlsen, Charles Ward Rhodes, Ralph H. Plumb, Geo. B. Zing, May C. Bristol, Wm. M. Chase, A.H. Griffith, Richard Lloyd Jones-Collier's Weekly, Charles M. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, December 16-20, 1904 (Reel 4818, Frame 174-190)
    (E.H. Plumb, Edmund Hayes, Allen B. Talcott, Dudley-Ogden Wood, Geo. F. Brownell, Robert David Gauley, Edmund Hayes, J.S. Royer)
  - Correspondence, December 21-31, 1904 (Reel 4818, Frame 191-229)
    (H. S. Hubbell, F. Morton, E.B. Green, Edmund Hayes, Albert E. Tansing, Edmund Hayes, Charles M. Kurtz, Henrich F. Albert-Assistant Imperial German Commissioner General, Geo. F. Brownell, M. Cassiday)
  - Correspondence, January 1-31, 1905 (Reel 4818, Frame 230-268)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Kurtz family, E.B. Green, Charles A. Ball-Louisiana Purchase Exposition Secretary, Emil Kegel, J. B. Bristol)
  - Correspondence, February 1-28, 1905 (Reel 4818, Frame 269-297)
    (Halsey C. Ives, Charles M. Kurtz, George H. Storey, Henry Wolf, Chas. H. Wyman-Custom House Brokers)
  - Correspondence, March 1-31, 1905 (Reel 4818, Frame 298-345)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Wm. H. Goodyear, R.B. Adam, A.W. Mesdag, L.A.C. Ward, Henry Wolf, Holmes Smith, D.M. Ellis-Lewis and Clark Exposition Commission, Cornelia Bentley Sage)
  - Correspondence, April 1-20, 1905 (Reel 4818, Frame 346-372)
    (Edward B. Green, Cornelia Bentley Sage, Charles M. Kurtz, Charles Ward Rhodes)
  - Correspondence, April 21-30, 1905 (Reel 4818, Frame 373-404)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Myron E. Pierce, Henry Wolf, Charles Ward Rhodes)
  - Correspondence, May 1-10, 1905 (Reel 4818, Frame 405-417)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Chas. H. Wyman-Custom House Brokers)
  - Correspondence, May 11-15, 1905 (Reel 4818, Frame 418-457)
    (Frederick E. Bartlett, A. H. Griffith, Charles M. Kurtz, H. Skiff-Field Columbian Museum, John B. Cauldwell, Rev. J. B. McCormick-Western University of Pennsylvania, Robert C. Ogden, Will H. Low, Marcus Benjamin, Geo. McKinstry, Mrs. A.M.G. Patterson, J.N. Marble)
  - Correspondence, May 16-25, 1905 (Reel 4818, Frame 458-478)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Philip B. Sawyer, Sam. P. Avery, W.J.L. Eurmont, Alaée Hortier, Frederick Dielman)
  - Correspondence, May 26-31, 1905 (Reel 4818, Frame 479-498)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Frederick W. Gookin, Will H. Low, Zelma Baylos, B.D. Woodward, Walter B. Stevens, Thomas Reid-The Glasgow Herald)
  - Correspondence, June 1-10, 1905 (Reel 4818, Frame 499-514)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Charles Sprague Pearce)
  - Correspondence, June 11-30, 1905 (Reel 4818, Frame 515-535)
    (George H. Storey-Metropolitan Museum of Art, George K. Andrews, Edmund Hayes, Charles M. Kurtz, J.B. Botto, E.L. Van Pelt, Emery H. Barton)
  - Correspondence, July-August, 1905 (Reel 4818, Frame 536-564)
    (Holmes Smith, Marcus Benjamin, Charles Ward Rhodes, Frederick G. Gray, R. Macaulay Stevenson, Maria Riker, Alice R. Alice R. Glenny, ? Curley, Alex Reid, C.J. Zolnay, Starkweather family, G.P. Sawyer, Charles M. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, September-October, 1905 (Reel 4818, Frame 565-598)
    (Geo. McKinstry, R. Macaulay Stevenson, Halsey C. Ives, Charles M. Kurtz, W.Y. Macgregor, Charles L. Freer, John Harrison Mills, Lydia Avery Coonley Ward, Russia's First Fine Arts Exposition in America, Edmund H. Wuerpel)
  - Correspondence, November 1-30, 1905 (Reel 4818, Frame 599-618)
    (Dudley W. Rhodes, W. Gardner, J.B. Botto, Stephenson family, Alexander Roche, Peter A. Schemm, Hermon A. Kelley-Cleveland Museum of Art, James D. Spriggs)
  - Correspondence, December 1-31, 1905 (Reel 4818, Frame 619-643)
    (Alexander Roche, Charles, M. Kurtz, John W. Alexander, Grosvenor Thomas, Halsey C. Ives, S. Kellogg, Emery H. Barton, Charles M. Kurtz, Lydia Avery Coonley Ward)
  - Correspondence, January 1-31, 1906, undated (Reel 4818, Frame 644-670)
    (Charles Caryl Coleman, Geo. E. Matthers, Alexander Roche, Halsey C. Ives, A.W. Mesdag, Stuart Park, Henry Wolf, John McGibbons-Louisiana Purchase Exposition, J.B. Botto)
  - Correspondence, February 1-28, 1906 (Reel 4818, Frame 671-699)
    (Julia S. Kurtz, Henry Wolf, Starkweather family, Halsey C. Ives, Gustave Kobbe, Charles M. Kurtz, Dudlle-Frank V. Dudley?, John Stevenson, Jr.-Driggs-Seabury Ordnance Corporation, J. Whitelaw Hamilton)
  - Correspondence, March 1-31, 1906 (Reel 4818, Frame 700-735)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Halsey C. Ives, Kurtz family, J. Carroll Beckwith, James D. Spriggs, Emery H. Barton, Marian De Forest)
  - Correspondence, April 1-10, 1906 (Reel 4818, Frame 736-762)
    (sympathy notes on death of Davis B. Kurtz, R. Lesch-Berlin Photographic Company), Geo. F. Brownell, John Stevenson, Jr., Carlton Sprague, Halsey C. Ives, Frances E. A. Curley)
  - Correspondence, April 11-20, 1906 (Reel 4818, Frame 763-798)
    (Halsey C. Ives, Carleton Sprague, Henry Wolf, Charles M. Kurtz, Alice R. Glenny, Alexander Roche, Marcus Benjamin)
  - Correspondence, April 21-30, 1906 (Reel 4818, Frame 799-821)
    (Halsey C. Ives, Charles M. Kurtz, J.B. Botto)
  - Correspondence, May 1-31, 1906 (Reel 4818, Frame 822-841)
    (Mrs. L.A. Coonley Ward, Charles M Kurtz, Stephenson family, W.Y. Macgregor, Julia S. Kurtz, George Houston)
  - Correspondence, June 1-30, 1906 (Reel 4818, Frame 842-858)
    (Marcus Benjamin, Mrs. R. M. Stevenson, Starkweather family, Charles M. Kurtz, George Houston)
  - Correspondence, July 1-30, 1906 (Reel 4818, Frame 859-882)
    (Stephenson family, Charles M. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, August-October, 1906 (Reel 4818, Frame 883-908)
    (Carl Marr, Julia S. Kurtz, Charles M. Kurtz, Frank V.? Dudley, Stephenson family, Henry Wolf, J.P.H. Cunningham, Halsey C. Ives)
  - Correspondence, November 1-30, 1906 (Reel 4818, Frame 909-934)
    (Henry Wolf, F.W. Stokes, Librarian, National Academy of Design, Charles M. Kurtz, Alexander Roche)
  - Correspondence, December 1-31, 1906 (Reel 4818, Frame 935-962)
    (Henry Wolf, Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, Stephenson family, Henry Wolf, George Pirie, E. H. Wuerpel)
  - Correspondence, Jan.-Feb. 1907 (Reel 4818, Frame 963-990)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Chas. S. Weaver, Mrs. L.A. C. Ward)
  - Correspondence, March 1-31, 1907 (Reel 4818, Frame 991-1015)
    (Helen A. Robinson, Mrs. L.A.C. Ward, Charles M. Kurtz, Augustus Koopman, D. Heinemann, Stephenson family)
  - Correspondence, April 1-10, 1907 (Reel 4818, Frame 1016-1029)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Stephenson family)
  - Correspondence, April 11-30, 1907 (Reel 4818, Frame 1030-1064)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Stephenson family, Frank W. Sweitzer)
  - Correspondence, May 1-15, 1907 (Reel 4818, Frame 1065-1091)
  - Correspondence, May 16-31, 1907 (Reel 4818, Frame 1092-1117)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Mrs. L.A.C. Ward, Stephenson family)
  - Correspondence, June 1-20, 1907 (Reel 4818, Frame 1118-1137)
  - Correspondence, June 21-30, 1907 (Reel 4818, Frame 1138-1157)
  - Correspondence, July 1-30, 1907 (Reel 4818, Frame 1158-1196)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Stephenson family, Harry Watrous-National Academy of Design)
  - Correspondence, August 1-31, 1907 (Reel 4818, Frame 1197-1232)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, E.H. Wuerpel, Dudley-Ogden Wood)
  - Correspondence, September 1-30, 1907 (Reel 4818, Frame 1233-1269)
    (Mary T. Martin, Stephenson family, Harry Watrous, Charles M. Kurtz, Dudley-Ogden Wood)
  - Correspondence, October-November, 1907 (Reel 4818, Frame 1270-1285)
    (Stephenson family, Robert Barclay, Charles M. Kurtz, Cornelia Bentley Sage)
  - Correspondence, December 1-31, 1907 (Reel 4818, Frame 1286-1308)
    (Stephenson family, Charles M. Kurtz, Mrs. L.A.C. Ward, Henry Wolf)
  - Correspondence, January 1-31, 1908 (Reel 4819, Frame 1-44)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Francis Wilson, Stephenson family, Julia S. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, February-March, 1908 (Reel 4819, Frame 44-59)
    (Arthur Stedman, Mrs. L.A. C. Ward, Stephenson family, Charles M. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, April-May, 1908 (Reel 4819, Frame 60-93)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, David Lloyd-John Lane Co., Publishers, Will H. Low, Cornelia Bentley Sage)
  - Correspondence, June-July, 1908 (Reel 4819, Frame 94-108)
    (Cornelia Bentley Sage, Charles M. Kurtz, Stephenson family)
  - Correspondence, August 1-31, 1908 (Reel 4819, Frame 109-146)
    (Julia Wilder Kurtz, Charles M. Kurtz, Mrs. L. A. C. Ward, Stephenson family)
  - Correspondence, September 1-30, 1908 (Reel 4819, Frame 147-172)
    (Julia Wilder Kurtz, Mrs. L.A.C. Ward, Stephenson family)
  - Correspondence, October 1-31, 1908 (Reel 4819, Frame 173-206)
    (George F. Kunz, Stephenson family, Julia Wilder Kurtz, Charles M. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, November 1-30, 1908 (Reel 4819, Frame 207-227)
    (Julia Wilder Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, December 1-31, 1908 (Reel 4819, Frame 228-271)
    (G.L. Berg-Alaska-Yukon-Pacific Exposition, Charles M. Kurtz, Julia Wilder Kurtz, Stephenson family)
  - Correspondence, January 1-31, 1909 (Reel 4819, Frame 272-291)
    (Joaquin Sorolla-in French, Julia Wilder Kurtz, Charles M. Kurtz, Cornelia B. Sage)
  - Correspondence, February 1-23, 1909 (Reel 4819, Frame 292-309)
    (Archer M. Huntington, Charles M. Kurtz, Julia S. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, March 1-10, 1909 (Reel 4819, Frame 310-331)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Julia Wilder Kurtz, Cornelia Bentley Sage, Stephenson family)
  - Correspondence, March 11-20, 1909 (Reel 4819, Frame 332-346)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Cornelia Bentley Sage, Starkweather family, J. D. Spriggs, E. L. Van Pelt, Halsey C. Ives, Frances R. Wheeler, Ogden Wood)
  - Correspondence, March 21, 1909-August 21, 1940 (Reel 4819, Frame 347-961)
    (correspondence in this section is posthumous and consists of many sympathy notes from family and friends on the death of Charles M. Kurtz as well as letters from Cornelia Bentley Sage, acting and later director of the Buffalo Academy of Fine Arts. Also included is correspondence relating to estates in both the Kurtz and Stephenson families and miscellaneous letters to Julia S. Kurtz and her daughters from friends and family.)
  - Correspondence Re: Academy Notes, 1843-1940, undated (Reel 4819, Frame 965-1007)
    (Otto H. Bacher, Alice Barber, J. Jay Barber)
  - Academy Notes, Be-Br, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1008-1027)
    (W. H. Beard, J. Carroll Beckwith, Carl C. Breumer)
  - Academy Notes, Br continued [sic] (Reel 4819, Frame 1028-1060)
    (Charles Bridgman, J.B. Bristol, Wm. M. Brown, Jennie Brownscombe, Georgine Campbell, Thomas Carter, J.W. Casilear)
  - Academy Notes, CAS, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1061-1072)
    (Cassell & Co.)
  - Academy Notes, CH-CO, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1073-1086)
    (Harry Chase, F.S. Church, Thomas B. Clarke, C.W. Conant, Kenyon Cox)
  - Academy Notes, CR, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1087-1099)
    (Thomas B. Craig, Bruce Crane, J. F. Cropsey)
  - Academy Notes, D-E, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1100-1116)
    (Wm. P. W. Dana, F.S. Dellenbaugh, C.M. Dewey, Sarah P.B. Dodson, C. Harry Eaton)
  - Academy Notes, F, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1117-1134)
    (Wm. Bailey Faxon, Henry A. Ferguson, Fred. W. Freer)
  - Academy Notes, E, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1135-1155)
    (Edward Gay, Sallie J. Gibbons, W. Hamilton Gibson, R. Swain Gifford, Eliza Greatorex, R.H. Griffin)
  - Academy Notes, Ha, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1156-1169)
    (Hamilton Hamilton, C.Y.Turner, Harper & Bros.)
  - Academy Notes, Hi-Hv, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1170-1187)
    (Winslow Homer, Thomas Hovenden, Wendell Stanton Howard, Alfred C. Howland, D. Huntington)
  - Academy Notes, I-J, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1188-1199)
    (Benoni Irwin, Eastman Johnson, H. Bolton Jones)
  - Academy Notes, K, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1200-1211)
    (F.L. Kirkpatrick, Mary Kollock)
  - Academy Notes, L, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1212-1229)
    (George C. Lambdin, W.H. Lippincott, Will H. Low, Joseph Lyman)
  - Academy Notes, Ma-Mc, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1230-1248)
    (S.R. MacKnight, Montague Marks, Constant Mayer, Jervis McEntee, C.M. McIlhenny)
  - Academy Notes, Mc, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1249-1257)
    (Geo. A. McKinstry)
  - Academy Notes, Me-Mi, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1258-1266)
    (Gari Melchers, C.H. Miller, Francis Miller)
  - Academy Notes, Mo, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1267-1281)
    (J.A.S. Monks, E. Augustus Moore, Edward Moran, Percy Moran, Peter Moran)
  - Academy Notes, N, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1282-1293)
    (David Neal, B.H. Nicholls, J.C. Nicoll, Stansbury Norse)
  - Academy Notes, P, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1294-1308)
    (Stephen Parrish, Arthur Parton)
  - Academy Notes, R, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1309-1326)
    (Arthur Quartley, George D. Rand, G. Reichard, William T. Richards, H.W. Robbins, F. Rondel, P.P. Ruder)
  - Academy Notes, Sa-Sh, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1327-1342)
    (William Sartain, Walter Satterlee, F. Schnchardt, R.M. Shurtleff)
  - Academy Notes, Si-Sp, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1343-1353)
    (Francis A. Silva, Geo. H. Smillie, T.L. Smith, Wm. L. Sonntag)
  - Academy Notes, St, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1354-1367)
    (H.S. Stevenson, G.H. Story, J.B. Sword)
  - Academy Notes, T, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1368-1389)
    (Wordsworth Thompson, Virgillo Tojetti, J.M. Tracy, N.H. Trotter, James G. Tyler)
  - Academy Notes, V, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1390-1398)
    (C. F. Ulrich, Charles M. Kurtz, R. W. Van Boskerck, J.C. Van Dyke, K. Van Elton)
  - Academy Notes, Wa, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1399-1411)
    (Frank Waller, Warren, Fuller & Lange)
  - Academy Notes, We-Wi, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1412-1425)
    (J. Alden Weir, J. B. Whittaker, W. Whittredge, Carleton WIggins, Lemuel M. Wiles, John Williamson)
  - Academy Notes, Wo-Y, 1884 (Reel 4819, Frame 1426-1436)
    (Geo. B. Wood, Thomas W. Wood, M. Angelo Woolf, C.L. Wright, A.H. Wyant, Geo. H. Yewell)
  - Academy Notes, A-Bi 1886 (Reel 4819, Frame 1437-1453)
    (J. Jay Barbor, Alban Jasper Conant, Pierre Marie Boyle, Albert Bierstadt, Ernest F. Birmingham)
  - Academy Notes, Bl, 1886 (Reel 4819, Frame 1454-1467)
    (Edwin Howland Blashfield, Carl Bremer, Hugo Breul, J. R. Brevoort, J. S. Bradley, Charles Bridgman, Wm. B. Butler)
  - Academy Notes, C, 1886 (Reel 4819, Frame 1468-1486)
    (Charles C. Curran, Cassell & Co., Carlton T. Chapman, F. S. Church, Thomas B. Clark, Gabrielle D. Clements, Bruce Crane, J. F. Cropsey)
- Circulars/Requests for Submissions of Works of Art, 1886-1905, Series 3:
  This series consists primarily of standardized forms listing the title of the work of art, size, condition of frames, location, catalogue price and insurance value. These were completed by various artists and describe paintings being submitted to exhibitions organized by Charles M. Kurtz. The most extensive group are those that pertain to the 1886 Southern Exposition at Louisville, Kentucky.
  The Southern Exposition was visited annually by half a million people from all parts of the country. It offered not only an art exhibition, but also general exhibitions of natural and manufactured products as well as musical concerts. In 1886, a dispute between the directors of the Art Department of the Louisville Exposition and the trustees of the American Art Association regarding the Prize Fund exhibition, created difficulties in obtaining some of the works specified. Consequently, interspersed among the application forms in this subseries are letters that document this altercation.
  Application forms for the St. Louis Exposition and Music Hall Association exhibitions from 1893-1897 and two exhibitions of paintings by the Glasgow School: in 1895 in St. Louis and in 1905 at the Albright Art Gallery in Buffalo, New York, are also found in this series. Along with these forms are biographical statements from the artists and descriptive information regarding some of the paintings. Occasionally, as in the case of George I. Seney, works owned and loaned by noted collectors are also listed.
  - Southern Exposition, Louisville, Ky., 1886 (Reel 4820)
    - Artist surnames, A-B (Reel 4820, Frame 671-718)
    - Artist surnames, C (Reel 4820, Frame 719-753)
    - Artist surnames, D-E (Reel 4820, Frame 754-800)
    - Artist surnames, F-G (Reel 4820, Frame 801-841)
    - Artist surnames, H-J (Reel 4820, Frame 842-909)
    - Artist surnames, K-L (Reel 4820, Frame 910-964)
    - Artist surnames, M-O (Reel 4820, Frame 965-1014)
    - Artist surnames, P-R (Reel 4820, Frame 1015-1078)
    - Artist surnames, S-Z (Reel 4820, Frame 1079-1165)
  - St. Louis Exposition and Music Hall Association, Miscellaneous 1893-1897 (Reel 4820, Frame 1168-1178)
  - Glasgow School Exhibition, St. Louis, 1895 (Reel 4820)
    - Artist surnames, A-K (Reel 4820, Frame 1183-1213)
    - Artist surnames, L-Z (Reel 4820, Frame 1214-1235)
  - Glasgow School Exhibition, Buffalo, Albright Art Gallery, 1905 (Reel 4820, Frame 1236-1263)
- Legal Records, 1881-1928, Series 4:
  Legal documents in this series include memoranda of agreements between Charles M. Kurtz and various business firms, deeds and related material regarding real estate owned by the Stephenson family, and last wills and testaments of Stephenson family members.
  - Memorandum of agreement between Charles M. Kurtz and Cassell & Co., for the sale of American Academy Notes (Reel 4820, Frame 1268-69)
  - Property Deed, Stephenson family, 1881 (Reel 4820, Frame 1270)
  - Copyright for Illustrated Art Notes, National Academy of Design, 1882 (Reel 4820, Frame 1271-74)
  - Codicil to will of A.T. Stephenson (Reel 4820, Frame 1275)
  - Memoranda of agreement between Charles M. Kurtz and Moss Engraving Co. (Reel 4820, Frame 1276-1280)
  - Incorporation agreement, American Art Association, Jan. 2, 1885 (Reel 4820, Frame 1281-83)
  - Memorandum of agreement between American Art Association and the Southern Exposition, Louisville, Ky. re: fee for the first Prize Fund Exhibition, 1885 (Reel 4820, Frame 1284-1293)
  - Announcement of Prize Fund Exhibition by American Art Association, 1886 (Reel 4820, Frame 1295-97)
  - Minutes, Southern Exposition, 1886 (Reel 4820, Frame 1298)
  - Act of Incorporation, Boussod-Valadon Co., 1875 (Reel 4820, Frame 1300-1303)
  - Memoranda of Agreement between Committee for Danish Art in America and Charles M. Kurtz for the St. Louis Exposition, May, 1895 (Reel 4820, Frame 1304-1305)
  - Memorandum of agreement between Charles M. Kurtz and Eugene Fischof of Paris, May, 1900 (Reel 4820, Frame 1306)
  - Deed of Conveyance, Stephenson Family, 1907 (Reel 4820, Frame 1308-11)
  - Last Will and Testament of Mary A. Stephenson, 1920-24 (Reel 4820, Frame 1312-14)
  - Contract of purchase for Stephenson house, 1928 (Reel 4820, Frame 1315)
- Financial Material, 1870-1989, undated, Series 5:
  This series is arranged into four subseries.
  5.1: Inventories and Price Lists of Kurtz's Collections, 1870-1989, undated
  5.2: Ledgers, 1877-1909
  5.3: Art-Related Expenses, 1884-1919, undated
  5.4: Miscellaneous Expenses, 1880-1948, undated
  - Inventories and Price Lists of Kurtz's Collections, 1870-1989, undated, 5.1:
    - Account book of coins, July, 1870 (Reel 4821, Frame 002-48)
    - Inventory book--personal possessions, paintings, electroplate designs from 1881-1888 for Academy Notes, library book arrangement, May, 1888 (Reel 4821, Frame 049-107)
    - Inventory book--listing of art owned by Charles M. Kurtz and placement of it within his home, personal possessions contained within trunks and storage boxes, insurance policy, August 1888 (Reel 4821, Frame 108-131)
    - Inventory book--personal possessions of Charles M. Kurtz and storage location, including: paintings, coins and medals, photographs, lantern slides, pottery and porcelain, books by topics, floor plan of Kurtz apartment at 100 W. 78 Street, New York City, January 1, 1898 (Reel 4821, Frame 132-231)
    - Inventory listing assets of D. B. Kurtz Estate, January 1, 1898 (Reel 4821, Frame 232-233)
    - Appraisal of the Charles M. Kurtz estate, April 7, 1909 (Reel 4821, Frame 234-242)
    - Inventory and valuation of paintings sold at auction, February 24, 1910 (Reel 4821, Frame 243-251)
    - Inventory of the Kurtz Collection--listing by Isabel Kurtz of art purchased between 1904-1908 and place of purchase circa 1904-1908 (Reel 4821, Frame 252-270)
    - Inventory of Kurtz Collection--notes by Isabel Kurtz, 1902-1910 (Reel 4821, Frame 271)